Kelvin Liusiani

AI Engineer

Phone +62 813 3621 4840 **Email** kelvinliu04@gmail.com

LinkedIn www.linkedin.com/in/kelvin-liusiani

GitHub www.github.com/kelvinliu04

An **AI enthusiast** with over two years of continual learning and experience in **Data Science** and **Computer Vision**. Very passionate with new technology, I routinely read new and SOTA research. And love to be engineer, who always solving any problem that I am facing with logical thinking and fundamental skills. Now, I am looking for **Artificial Intelligence** position with company that **appreciates person who has high desire to learn** and **supportive works environment**.



Education

Aug 2016 - Jan 2020

BE in Electrical Engineering, Institute Technology of Sepuluh Nopember(ITS) with Cum Laude Honor (3.5 years)

GPA: 3.81 / 4.00

Thesis: "Dataset Maker System using Gaussian Mixture Model (GMM) Method for Object Learning"

- Creating Dataset of 360° of Household Objects using Kinect V2 with GMM for object segmentation.
- This Dataset contains of labels, object segmentations (RGB, Near-Infrared, and Depth map) and volume of objects.

Research

March - July 2019

JAREE - Journal on Advanced Research in Electrical Engineering

Volume 4, Number 1, April 2020

Journal Title: "Object Extraction Using Probabilistic Maps of Color, Depth, and Near-Infrared Information"

 By using probabilistic maps of color, depth and NIR from Kinect V2 modeled by Gaussian Mixture Model (GMM), object extraction can be done and used for creating object segmentation dataset and 3D object modeling dataset.

Working Experience

Feb 2020 - Present

Artificial Intelligence Engineer (Associate)

Synnex Metrodata Indonesia

- Train Deep Learning model (Faster-RCNN, MobileNet V2-SSD, Yolo, CenterNet, EfficientDet, etc) using some frameworks, like Tensorflow, Pytoch, and Caffe.
- Deploy solution on edge (without GPU) using Intel OpenVINO Toolkits and ONNX as an Inference.
- Creating some AI solutions from scratch: People Counting, Vehicle Counting, Face Recognition for Attendance System, Indonesian License Plate Recognition, Smart Digital Signage System, Face-Mask Alarm and Social Distancing Alarm

Nov 2019 - Feb 2020 **Artificial Intelligence Engineer (Intern)**

Reblood (Non-profit Startup)

- Create image classifier for the receipt proof of blood donor
- Using Google Cloud Vision for Text Detection and create automatic information retrieval using python
- Deploy on Google Cloud App Engine

Jul 2019 - Aug 2020 **Electronics/IoT Engineer (Intern)**

PT MISEL (Industrial Automation System)

Project: Pool and Jacuzzi Water Heater Automation IoT Based in Kapal Api's Villa at Trawas

- Build Water Heater Automation Controlled by Delta PLC (Two PLC)
- Build Three HMI (Human Machine Interface) for the boiler room, filter room and
- Connect them into IoT system using local wireless for Smartphone Controller

Non - Formal Education

Jan – July 2020	Student of Bangkit Academy
	Led by Google, Tokopedia, Gojek, & Traveloka
	An exclusive machine learning academy with very selected students
April – July 2020	Intel® Edge AI for IoT Developers Nanodegree Program
	Nanodegree program from Udacity and Intel with some project
Jul 2019 - Aug 2019	Artificial Intelligence Digital Talent Academy Scholarship
	by Indonesian Ministry of Communication and Information Technology
	Full time bootcamp within 2 months with some final – projects

Achievements

Nov 2020	9th/139 Place in National Data Science Challenge 2020 by Shopee
	Advanced category (tonic: Product Matchina)

	navancea category (topic. I rounce matering)	
Certifications		
2020	Intel® Edge AI for IoT Developers Nanodegree Udacity	
2020	Tensorflow Developer Certificate <i>Tensorflow</i>	
2020	Tensorflow in Practice Coursera and DeepLearning.ai	
2019	Image Processing with Python Track (3 Courses) DataCamp	
2019	Data Analyst with Python Track (16 Courses) DataCamp	
2019	Intermediate Python for Data Science DataCamp	
2019	SQL Fundamentals Track (4 Courses) DataCamp	